# 宁夏 吴忠
Wuzhong, Ningxia
# 雪鱼现在在黄河流域的宁夏吴忠
Xueyu is currently in Wuzhong, Ningxia, in the Yellow River Basin
# 这边的人真的是很会吃羊肉
The people here are really good at cooking mutton
# 他们对羊肉的吃法是从头吃到脚
They eat lambs from head to toe.
# 从里吃到外啊
From inside to outside
# 光是羊杂他们就有很多的讲究
Even a bowl of mutton offal soup is exquisite
# 走 去看一看
Follow me, let’s take a look
# 排队也费劲啊
The queue is so long
# 你好 后面的几位
Hello, next please
# 我要一份带走的
I want a takeout
# 好的
Sure
# 怎么说呢 大家会说来这个羊杂店会看到羊杂西施
Em, people said we can find the “mutton offal beauty” at this restaurant
# 真的是看了很多的什么什么西施 如油条西施 奶茶西施
We've seen see many beauties during our journey such as “youtiao (deep-fried dough strips) beauty” or “milk tea beauty”
# 这家的西施绝对的名不虚传
The “mutton offal beauty” is absolutely worthy of fame
# 啊 我的八宝茶上来了
Ah, my Babao Tea(traditional assorted herbal tea) is ready
# 它是宁夏的特色
This is the local specialty of Ningxia.
# 几乎每次吃饭都会点的
It's served at almost every meal
# 这里面是茶叶 冰糖 枸杞 沙枣 核桃 还有桂圆 芝麻 玫瑰花
The Babao tea is made with tea leaves, rock sugar, goji berries, silver berries (aka Russian olives), walnuts, and longan, sesame, roses
# 这里面是额外加的白糖吗
Is there extra sugar in it?
# 是的 白砂糖
Yes, we add some granulated sugar.
# 相机上的她真的是不上镜 现场看她
She is much more pretty than I recorded. When I look at her
# 我都感觉我看直了眼
I feel like… I can hardly move my eyes.
# 美的东西嘛 不管男的女的都喜欢看
You know, both men and women love beauty.
# 喝茶的功夫 羊杂就已经开始制作了
While I’m having my tea, they have started making my mutton offal soup.
# 现在这边在清洗羊肺
Now they are cleaning the mutton lung.
# 羊肺原来是血红色
The mutton lung was blood-red at the beginning.
# 需要用水不断地冲洗 冲到变成白色
It needs to be rinsed with water constantly until it turns white.
# 现在羊肺就像一个吹了气的鹅一样
Now the mutton lung is like a blown goose.
# 变得白白胖胖的
Turned into white and chubby.
# （洗掉面筋的面浆）
(Starch water without gluten)
# （这是面筋）
(This is gluten)
# 现在是准备开始灌羊肺
Now it's time to pump starch water into the mutton lung.
# 把面浆灌进去 水会渗出来一部分
Some water will permeate through the lung when pumping starch water inside.
# 这个肺啊 已经越来越大了
This lung is getting bigger.
# （蒸熟 放凉）
(Steam and let it cool)
# （羊头肉）
(Mutton head meat)
# （羊肝）
(Mutton liver)
# （羊肚）
(Mutton tripe)
# （羊心）
(Mutton heart)
# 切好的羊杂会和盐 辣子等一起放在羊肉汤里烩一下
Chopped offal will be stewed with salt and chili in the mutton soup.
# （蒜末）
(minced garlic)
# 哇 谢谢
Wow thank you
# 这个羊杂看起来就是红油辣子很浓郁
The mutton offal soup looks strong with red chili oil.
# 不吃它就这么闻着就觉得很香啊
Smells appetizing even before tasting.
# 看上去很大的量啊 20元一碗
20 yuan for each seems a lot.
# 热气腾腾的一碗 浓郁飘香
The steaming hot and fragrant offal soup.
# 这满满的一桌都是我的
It’s all mine.
# 分别是羊杂 八宝茶 还有晒的茄干 凉粉
Those are the mutton offal soup, the Babao tea, the dried eggplant, and the bean jelly.
# 这顿饭很丰盛啊
That was a big meal.
# 我们看看这碗羊杂里有什么东西吧
Let us see what's in this offal soup.
# 能够明显看到的就是羊肚
We can obviously find mutton tripe.
# 这个就是传说中的面肺了吧
This is the legendary “flour lung”.
# 除了面肺 羊肚
Besides flour lung, mutton tripe.
# 还有羊头肉 简单来说就说心肝肚肺头
We also have the mutton head meat. Basically, we have mutton heart, liver, tripe, lung, and head.
# 不多说了 赶快来尝一尝吧
Without further ado, let's have a bite.
# 这个羊杂浸入到辣子中真是香味扑鼻啊
The mutton offal soaked in chili really smells delicious
# （羊肝绵密）
Mutton liver has a soft and thick texture.
# 这个辣子应该是羊油辣子 吃起来特别的香
The red chili oil must be made with mutton tallow, delicious
# 该吃一个面肺了
Time to eat “flour lung”
# 毕竟面肺是吴忠羊杂和其他地方的羊杂之间的一个很重要的区别
After all, one of the major differences between Wuzhong’s mutton offal and others is they use the “flour lung”.
# 这个面肺好神奇的口感啊
This flour lung has interesting texture!
# 有点弹口 又有点像土豆泥这样的棉的口感
A bit al dente, but also have a bit soft texture like mush potato.
# 吃起来特别爽滑
It tastes very smooth
# 我觉得吴忠人对羊杂的吃法有点超乎我的想象
I think the way Wuzhong people cook mutton offal is a bit beyond my imagination
# 我根本想象不到 他们对羊肺还有自己独特的吃法
I couldn't imagine they have their unique cooking style for mutton lungs.
# 就是要把面灌入肺中 和羊杂搭配一起吃
Which pumps starch water into the lung and stew with mutton offal.
# 在做面肺前，一定要把面筋去掉 只灌入面浆
Before pumping “flour water” into the lung, make sure get rid of the gluten and just put in the starch water
# 如果说有面浆的话 可能会灌不进去 可能会堵塞
Otherwise, the gluten will block the water into the lung.
# 这么做出来的面肺真的是口感特别的润滑
The “flour lung” they made has a really smooth taste.
# 这边的羊肉羊杂吃起来一点都不膻
Their mutton meat and mutton offal have no gamey lamb smell at all.
# 有了这个面肺后 才觉得这碗羊杂是真正完美的
Only with this “flour lung” is the mutton offal soup perfect.
# 我觉得这碗羊杂就是一碗饭
I feel like the bowl itself can serve as a staple food.
# 如果你觉得吃不饱的话
If you are still not full
# 一个是吃这种白饼
You can either have this white flatbread.
# 另一个就是配这边的饸饹面
Or have their Hele Noodle.
# 两种都能顶饱
Both can fill your stomach.
# 吃羊杂的过程中 来一碗八宝茶 解腻又解辣
Babao tea can reduce both the grease and the spiciness from the mutton offal.
# 告别了小姐姐  我们今天的视频就到这儿
After saying goodbye to the beauty, that's the end of today's video
# 如果说 你觉得我的视频能够给你带来一些欢乐的话
If you enjoy our video.
# 记得关注哦 拜拜
Remember to subscribe, thanks for watching.